Guide to the University of Utah basketball films collection 1950-1985
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
University of Utah basketball films collection
1944-1985
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 (801) 581-8864
A0002
University of Utah
Approximately 1,300 16mm film reels and VHS videocassettes.
A collection of films of University of Utah basketball games.
Historical Note
The University of Utah Utes basketball team was founded in 1908. The team has finished its season among the National Collegiate Athelitcs Association's (NCAA) top-25 teams 19 times 1949-2009 and has played in the following conferences:
–1937: Rocky Mountain Athletic Conference
1938–1961: Skyline Conference
1962–1998: Western Athletic Conference (WAC)
1999–2010: Mountain West Conference
2011–: Pacific-12 Conference (Pac-12)
A collection of films of University of Utah basketball games and highlight reels. Footage dates are sporadic and range from 1944-1984.
Most of the collection is arranged chronologially by format and by content (complete game or highlight reel).
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
NCAA Basketball Tournament; Basketball--History; Sports and Recreation; Moving Images; moving images; sound recordings
- University of Utah basketball games on 16mm film, 1950-1985
  - Brigham Young University (BYU), 1950 January 28 (Reel 1)
    400 feet of 16mm film
  - Dixie Classic, 1959 (Reel 2)
    1200 feet of 16mm film
  - San Francisco, 1959 (Reel 3)
  - Colorado State (CSU), 1959 (Reel 4)
  - University of California Los Angeles (UCLA), 1959 (Reel 5)
  - Montana, 1959 (Reel 6)
  - CSU, 1960 (Reel 7)
  - BYU, 1960 (Reel 8)
  - Team unknown, 1960 (Reel 9)
  - Team unknown, 1960 (Reel 10)
  - Pennsylvania State University (Penn State), 1960 December 27 (Reel 11)
  - Arizona State, 1961 (Reel 12)
  - California State University (Cal State), 1961 (Reel 13)
  - University of Southern California (USC), 1961 (Reel 14)
  - Original Rosebud, 1962 (Reel 15)
  - CSU, 1962 (Reel 16)
  - Texas Western, 1962 December 15 (Reel 17)
    Score: 48-51
  - Wisconson, 1962 December 28 (Reel 18)
    Score: 72-94
  - Original Rosebud, 1963 (Reel 19)
  - Arizona, 1963 (Reel 20)
  - Wyoming, 1963 February 08 (Reel 21)
    Score: 104-73
  - BYU, 1963 (Reel 22)
  - Loyola, 1963 December 23 (Reel 23)
    Score: 99-77
  - Villanova, 1963 December 28 (Reel 24)
    Score: 75-82
  - Utah State, 1963 (Reel 25)
  - University of Cincinnati (Cincy), 1964 January 01 (Reel 26)
    Score: 76-68
  - Stanford, 1964 (Reel 27)
  - BYU, 1964 (Reel 28)
  - Arizona State, 1964 February 29 (Reel 29)
    Score: 78-103
  - Butler, 1964 (Reel 30)
  - Saint Mary's, 1964 (Reel 31)
  - San Jose State, 1964 (Reel 32)
  - California, 1964 (Reel 33)
  - Utah State, 1965 (Reel 34)
  - Arizona State, 1965 (Reel 35)
  - BYU, 1965 (Reel 36)
  - Wyoming, 1965 (Reel 37)
  - BYU, 1965 February 20 (Reel 38)
    Score: 99-108
  - Intro Squad, 1965 November 23 (Reel 39)
  - Loyola, 1965 (Reel 40)
  - Saint Mary's, 1965 (Reel 41)
  - San Jose State, 1965 (Reel 42)
  - Cincy, 1965 (Reel 43)
  - North Carolina (reel 1), 1965 December 30 (Reel 44)
  - North Carolina (reel 2), 1965 December 30 (Reel 45)
  - Wyoming, 1966 January 13 (Reel 46)
    Score: 93-81
  - Arizona, 1966 January 07 (Reel 47)
    Score: 87-88
  - University of Washington, 1966 (Reel 48)
  - Team unknown, 1966 (Reel 49)
    800 feet of 16mm film
  - Team unknown, 1966 (Reel 50)
  - Team unknown (reel 1), 1966 (Reel 51)
    600 feet of 16mm film
  - Loyola, 1966 February 10 (Reel 52)
    Score: 69-59
  - North Carolina State, 1966 December 21 (Reel 53)
    Scire: 86-76
  - Bradley (Sugar Bowl), 1966 December 30 (Reel 54)
    Score: 62-64
  - Utah State, 1967 January 07 (Reel 55)
    Score: 76-89
  - Arizona State, 1967 January 13 (Reel 56)
    Score: 84-71
  - Arizona State, 1967 (Reel 57)
  - Stanford, 1967 (Reel 58)
  - New Mexico, 1967 January 20 (Reel 59)
    Score: 66-64
  - Wyoming, 1967 (Reel 60)
  - BYU, 1967 February 11 (Reel 61)
  - BYU, 1967 Feburary 17 (Reel 62)
    Score: 60-61
  - Arizona State, 1967 March 04 (Reel 63)
    Score: 92-81
  - Team unknown, 1967 (Reel 64)
  - Colorado, 1967 December 04 (Reel 65)
    Score: 95-84
  - Wichita, 1967 (Reel 66)
  - Stanford, 1967 December 16 (Reel 67)
    Score: 101-92
  - USC, 1967 December 21 (Reel 68)
    Score: 87-84
  - Denver (reel 1), 1967 December 23 (Reel 69)
    Score: 99-87
  - Ghost Dance (2 reels), 1967 (Reel 70-71)
    1700 feet of 16mm film
  - Oregon (Far West Classic), 1967 December 28 (Reel 72)
    Score: 64-63
  - Arizona, 1968 (Reel 73)
  - New Mexico, 1968 (Reel 74)
  - Wyoming, 1968 (Reel 75)
  - University of Washington, 1968 January 26 (Reel 76)
    Score: 76-93
  - University of Washington, 1968 (Reel 77)
  - Utah State, 1968 February 03 (Reel 78)
    Score: 106-92
  - BYU, 1968 (Reel 79)
  - Oregon, 1968 (Reel 80)
  - University of Washington, 1968 (Reel 81)
  - Oregon State, 1968 (Reel 82)
  - CSU (Finals: Utah Classic), 1968 December 28 (Reel 83)
    Score: 58-70
  - Wyoming, 1969 (Reel 84)
  - New Mexico, 1969 January 16 (Reel 85)
    Scope: 77-76
  - Arizona State, 1969 January 23 (Reel 86)
    Scope: 88-93
  - Arizona, 1969 January 25 (Reel 87)
    Score: 64-90
  - Utah State, 1969 February 01 (Reel 88)
    Scope: 92-95
  - BYU, 1969 February 08 (Reel 89)
    Scope: 67-73
  - Arizona, 1970 (Reel 90)
  - Arizona, 1970 January 10 (Reel 91)
    Score: 79-74
  - Utah State, 1970 (Reel 92)
  - BYU, 1970 January 24 (Reel 93)
    Score: 91-81
  - USC, 1970 January 31 (Reel 94)
    Score: 73-78
  - Wyoming, 1970 (Reel 95)
  - CSU, 1970 February 07 (Reel 96)
    Score: 77-89
  - Arizona, 1970 February 12 (Reel 97)
    Score: 92-75
  - CSU, 1970 February 19 (Reel 98)
    Score: 69-83
  - Marquette, 1970 (Reel 99)
  - USC, 1970 December 04 (Reel 100)
    Score: 81-90
  - Utah State, 1970 December 05 (Reel 101)
    Score: 77-94
  - Oregon State, 1970 December 07 (Reel 102)
    Score: 71-95
  - Army, 1970 (Reel 103)
  - University of Pennsylvania (Penn) (Q.C.T. Spectrum), 1970 December 28 (Reel 104)
  - CSU (reel 1), 1971 February 19 (Reel 105)
    Score: 86-101
  - USC (3 reels), 1971 November 19 (Reel 106-108)
    Score: 67-79
  - BYU (reel 1), 1971 November 22 (Reel 109)
  - BYU (reel 2), 1971 November 22 (Reel 110)
  - Utah State (reel 1), 1971 December 04 (Reel 111)
  - Utah State (reel 2), 1971 December 04 (Reel 112)
    Sc0re: 93-74
  - Kansas State (reel 2), 1971 December 04 (Reel 113)
    Score: 59-65
  - Washington State (reel 2), 1971 December 18 (Reel 114)
    Score: 74-60
  - Northwestern (reel 1), 1971 December 23 (Reel 115)
    Score: 88-69
  - Northwestern (reel 2), 1971 December 23 (Reel 116)
  - University of Texas El Paso (UTEP), 1971 January 08 (Reel 117)
    Score: 56-81
    200 feet of 16mm film
  - Wyoming, 1971 (Reel 118)
  - CSU, 1971 (Reel 119)
  - Utah State, 1971 January 21 (Reel 120)
    Score: 92-102
  - Arizona, 1971 (Reel 121)
  - BYU, 1971 (Reel 122)
  - New Mexico, 1971 (Reel 123)
  - UTEP, 1971 (Reel 124)
  - Arizona State, 1971 (Reel 125)
  - Arizona State, 1971 (Reel 126)
  - BYU, 1971 (Reel 127)
  - Rutgers National Invitation Tournament (NIT) (reel 1), 1974 March 17 (Reel 128)
  - Rutgers National Invitation Tournament (NIT) (reel 1), 1974 March 17 (Reel 129)
    Score: 102-89
  - Arizona (floor shots), 1976 February 13 (Reel 130)
  - Pepperdine, 1979 March 09 (Reel 131)
    Score: 88-92
  - BYU (6 reels), 1983 January 25 (Reel 132-137)
    2800 feet of 16mm film
  - BYU (first half in slow motion), 1983 (Reel 138)
  - Air Force (reel 1), 1983 March 12 (Reel 139)
  - Air Force (reel 2), 1983 March 12 (Reel 140)
  - Air Force, 1985 (Reel 141)
- Highlight Films, 1950-1983
  - BYU, 1950 January 28 (Reel 1)
  - Dixie Classic, 1959 (Reel 2)
  - San Francisco, 1959 (Reel 3)
  - CSU, 1959 (Reel 4)
  - UCLA, 1959 (Reel 5)
  - Montana, 1959 (Reel 6)
  - CSU, 1960 (Reel 7)
  - BYU, 1960 (Reel 8)
  - Team unknown, 1960 (Reel 9)
  - Team unknown, 1960 (Reel 10)
  - Penn State, 1960 December 27 (Reel 11)
  - Arizona State, 1961 (Reel 12)
  - Cal State, 1961 (Reel 13)
  - USC, 1961 (Reel 14)
  - Original Rosebud, 1962 (Reel 15)
  - CSU, 1962 (Reel 16)
  - Texas Western, 1962 December 15 (Reel 17)
  - Wisconson, 1962 December 28 (Reel 18)
  - Original Rosebud, 1963 (Reel 19)
  - Arizona, 1963 (Reel 20)
  - Wyoming, 1963 February 08 (Reel 21)
  - BYU, 1963 (Reel 22)
  - Loyola, 1963 December 02 (Reel 23)
  - Villanova, 1963 December 28 (Reel 24)
  - Utah State, 1963 (Reel 25)
  - Cincy, 1964 January 01 (Reel 26)
  - Stanford, 1964 (Reel 27)
  - BYU, 1964 (Reel 28)
  - Arizona State, 1984 February 29 (Reel 29)
  - Butler, 1964 (Reel 30)
  - Saint Mary's, 1964 (Reel 31)
  - San Jose State, 1964 (Reel 32)
  - California, 1964 (Reel 33)
  - Utah State, 1965 (Reel 34)
  - Arizona State, 1965 (Reel 35)
  - BYU, 1965 (Reel 36)
  - Wyoming, 1965 (Reel 37)
  - BYU, 1965 February 20 (Reel 38)
  - Intro Squad, 1965 November 23 (Reel 39)
  - Loyola, 1965 (Reel 40)
  - Saint Mary's, 1965 (Reel 41)
  - San Jose State, 1965 (Reel 42)
  - Cincy, 1965 (Reel 43)
  - North Carolina (reel 1), 1965 December 30 (Reel 44)
  - North Carolina (reel 1), 1965 December 30 (Reel 45)
  - Wyoming, 1966 January 13 (Reel 46)
  - Arizona, 1966 January 07 (Reel 47)
  - University of Washington, 1966 (Reel 48)
  - Team unknown, 1966 (Reel 49)
  - Team unknown, 1966 (Reel 50)
  - Loyola (reel 1), 1966 (Reel 51)
  - Loyola (reel 2), 1966 December 10 (Reel 52)
  - North Carolina State, 1966 December 21 (Reel 53)
    Score: 86-76
  - Bradley (Sugar Bowl), 1966 December 30 (Reel 54)
  - Utah State, 1967 January 07 (Reel 55)
  - Arizona State, 1967 January 13 (Reel 56)
  - Arizona State, 1967 (Reel 57)
  - Stanford (reel 2), 1967 (Reel 58)
  - New Mexico, 1967 January 20 (Reel 59)
  - Wyoming, 1967 (Reel 60)
  - BYU, 1967 February 11 (Reel 61)
  - BYU, 1967 February 17 (Reel 62)
  - Arizona State, 1967 March 04 (Reel 63)
  - Team unknown, 1967 (Reel 64)
  - Colorado, 1967 February 04 (Reel 65)
  - Wichita, 1967 (Reel 66)
  - Stanford, 1967 December 16 (Reel 67)
  - USC, 1967 December 21 (Reel 68)
  - Denver, 1967 December 23 (Reel 69)
  - Ghost Dance (2 reels), 1967 (Reel 70-71)
  - Oregon (Far West Classic), 1967 December 28 (Reel 72)
  - Arizona, 1968 (Reel 73)
  - New Mexico, 1968 (Reel 74)
  - Basketball highlights (3 reels), 1956-1957 (Reel 75-77)
    3600 feet of 16mm film
  - Basketball highlights (3 reels), 1957-1958 (Reel 78-80)
  - Basketball highlights, 1958-1959 (Reel 81)
  - Basketball highlights (4 reels), 1959-1960 (Reel 82-85)
    4800 feet of 16mm film
  - Basketball highlights, 1960-1961 (Reel 86)
  - Basketball highlights (6 reels), 1961-1962 (Reel 87-92)
    7200 feet of 16mm film
  - Basketball highlights (6 reels), 1967-1968 (Reel 93-98)
  - Basketball highlights (4 reels), 1968-1969 (Reel 99-102)
    3200 feet of 16mm film
  - Utah: A Winning Way of Life, 197-/77 (Reel 103)
  - Basketball highlights, 1976-1977 (Reel 104)
  - Basketball highlights, 1977-1978 (Reel 105)
  - Basketball Highlight (4 reels), 1978-1979 (Reel 105-108)
  - Basketball highlights (2 reels), 1979-1980 (Reel 109-110)
  - Basketball highlights (champions) (2 reels), 1980-1981 (Reel 111-112)
    2400 feet of 16mm film
  - Basketball highlights, 1981 (Reel 113)
  - Basketball highlights, 1982-1983 (Reel 114)
- Miscellaneous basketball film reels
  - University of Utah basketball (19 reels), undated (Reel 1-19)
    Reels of unlabelled 16mm basketball films.
  - University of Utah basketball: Jerry Pimm, undated (Reel 20)
    Negative, optical soundtrack
  - University of Utah basketball action, undated (Reel 21)
  - Convention Version: A Going Place, 1973 January 19 (Reel 22)
  - University of Utah basketball conditioning drills, undated (Reel 23)
  - University of Utah basketball pressure team defense), undated (Reel 24)
  - University of Utah Basketball: A Day at the U, undated (Reel 25)
  - Lasalle, undated (Reel 21)
    1200 feet of 35mm film
- Basketball films on VHS, 1944-1983
  - University of Utah NCAA Tournament, 1944 (Cassette 1)
  - University of Utah NCAA Tournament (Madison Square Garden), 1944 (Cassette 2)
  - St. John's (2 cassettes), 1944 (Cassette 3-4)
    NCAA champion Utah plays NIT champion St. John's for a Red Cross benefit
  - University of Massachusettes (Mass), 1947 December 19 (Cassette 5)
  - BYU, 1947 (Cassette 6)
  - NIT (Madison Square Garden), 1947 (Cassette 7)
  - BYU, 1948 January 17 (Cassette 8)
  - Wyoming, 1948 March 06 (Cassette 9)
  - BYU, 1963 February 23 (Cassette 10)
  - Basketball highlights, 1967-68 (Cassette 11)
  - Institute of the American West: That Awesome Space, undated (Cassette 12)
  - Rutgers NIT, 1974 March 17 (Cassette 13)
  - Basketball highlights (Champions), 1980-1981 (Cassette 14)
  - Western Athletic Conference (WAC) Highlights, 1982-1983 (Cassette 15)
  - BYU, 1983 February 05 (Cassette 16)
    Score: 75-72
- 2002 addendum, 1944-1956
  - St. John's, 1944 (Reel 1)
    1000 feet of 16mm film
  - Wyoming (2 reels), 1947 (Reel 2)
  - Wyoming, 1947 (Reel 3)
  - St. John's, 1947 (Reel 4)
  - Utah State, 1948 February 07 (Reel 5)
  - Denver, 1949 December 09 (Reel 6)
  - Long Island, 1949 February 02 (Reel 7)
  - Long Island, 1949 February 02 (Reel 8)
  - Utah State, 1949 February 07 (Reel 9)
  - Colorado A&M (now CSU), 1949 February 28 (Reel 10)
  - Colorado A&M, 1949 February 28 (Reel 11)
  - Denver, 1949 March 04 (Reel 12)
  - Denver, 1949 March 05 (Reel 13)
  - Denver, 1949 March 05 (Reel 14)
  - Saint Joseph's, undated (Reel 15)
  - Team unknown, undated (Reel 16)
  - Team unknown, undated (Reel 17)
  - University of Washington, 1956 (Reel 18)